Contact

malachirose@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/malachirose (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Mobile Marketing
Online Advertising
Online Marketing

Certifications

Certification in Gamification

Malachi Rose

Building and growing world-changing start-ups San Francisco Bay Area

Summary

Malachi Rose is the Vice President of Growth at Mavan, network of in and on-demand veteran specialists who are experts at scaling startup concepts and businesses from A to C. More specifically, he's a mobile growth veteran who has spent the last decade growing some of the preeminent mobile gaming and fintech companies in the world.

Prior to joining Mavan, Malachi was Head of Growth Marketing at Digit from 2018-2021, and Director - Growth Marketing at Zynga from 2015-2018. While at Zynga, he led growth across all products, was responsible for nine-figure annual advertising budgets, built the growth marketing team, and helped the company achieve a profitable turnaround during his tenure. From 2013-2015, Malachi was Director - Marketing and User Acquisition for Rumble, and he was Senior Mobile Marketing Manager for Crowdstar from 2011-2013. He also worked in marketing for Epsilon and Fisher Investments.

He graduated with honors from the University of Colorado Boulder -Leeds School of Business.

How may I help you?

I'm a mobile marketer with deep experience building successful programs from the ground up. I have managed and executed numerous mobile app launches and have experience driving programs from soup-to-nuts. I'm always abreast of mobile industry trends and passionate about the intersection of marketing and technology.

Specialties:

Growth strategy

- Performance Marketing / Mobile User Acquisition / Facebook & Paid Social UA
- Unpaid / Viral Growth
- iOS and Android app launches
- Performance Analytics
- A/B & Multivariate Testing
- Campaign Optimization
- Online / Display Advertising
- Media Buying
- Retargeting / Re-engagement
- Customer Relationship Marketing (CRM)

Experience

MAVAN

VP of Growth

February 2021 - Present (4 years 8 months)

San Francisco Bay Area

Malachi Rose is the Vice President of Growth at Mavan, an exclusive network of senior leaders from the fastest-growing companies in tech. We apply the methods we've pioneered over the last 15 years to validate and grow our client's startups – from series A to C.

We are experts in strategy, data, marketing, creative, product, and engineering who work with internal leaders to help grow their startups. After analyzing their needs, we deliver recommendations, align on strategy, and deploy the right people with the right skills at the right time to deliver against their unique growth goals. We work as an extension of their team integrating seamlessly with existing leadership, employees, and external partners.

Malachi leads growth strategy across Mavan's clients and venture studio companies, helping them to design and execute highly sophisticated growth strategies and achieve successful outcomes. By taking the best aspects from top-down planning and bottoms-up research, the Mavan team of experts can quickly and efficiently identify and solve growth constraints and unlock the next level of scale for companies.

Digit
Head of Growth Marketing
November 2018 - January 2021 (2 years 3 months)

Page 2 of 6

San Francisco

Member of the Senior Leadership team at Digit and the first marketing hire, responsible for owning growth strategy and building out the foundation that would enable Digit to scale rapidly. Reported into the COO and provided guidance to executive leadership on all things growth related. Partnered closely with Product Marketing, Growth Eng, Data Science and Finance to achieve cross-functional OKR goals.

- Grew ARR 3x over the course of first 1.5 years and took company from Series B to successful Series C fundraise; leading to a successful exit for \$212mm in 2021
- Built out a world-class growth function
- Scaled paid marketing from seven to eight-figure budgets, while maintaining healthy LTV-to-CAC
- Helped put Digit on the map as one of the leading fintech apps in the market

Digit makes financial health effortless for everyone by intelligently analyzing and automating a user's personal finances. We're using machine learning and behavioral psychology to build groundbreaking personalization technology to make financial health approachable, simple, and automatic for our members. In doing so, our members can focus on other important parts of their lives, knowing that Digit has them covered. To date, Digit has saved our members more than \$2.5 billion.

Zynga

3 years 5 months

Director - Growth Marketing July 2016 - August 2018 (2 years 2 months)

San Francisco, California

- Oversaw User Acquisition team responsible for managing a nine-figure annual marketing budget.
- Led strategy for paid social channels (Facebook, Snap, Twitter).
- Responsible for building and scaling paid re-marketing efforts.
- Led numerous worldwide product launches across multiple key titles (Words with Friends, FarmVille 2, and others).
- Increased organic growth on emerging platforms (i.e. Facebook Instant Games) and lead cross-discipline teams on marketing strategy.
- Marketing tech stack development and 3rd party sourcing.

Senior Manager - User Acquistion

April 2015 - June 2016 (1 year 3 months)

San Francisco, CA

Managed growth strategy across several of Zynga's core product franchises. Drove a systematic redesign of Zynga's BI and data tools to help advance our capabilities. Helped to hire and develop the UA team's headcount to more than double the size.

Rumble

Director - Marketing & User Acquisition November 2013 - March 2015 (1 year 5 months)

San Mateo, CA

Lead global marketing strategy across Rumble's portfolio of mobile and web apps. Focused on growing our audience of loyal players across multiple platforms - mobile (iOS & Android), browser, Facebook. Reporting directly to EVP.

Rumble's mission is to create the most engaging and fulfilling online game experiences on the planet. We are unique in our focus on the gamer audience and our exacting standards around quality gameplay. By combining the best of AAA game design with free-to-play accessibility, we believe we will change the way gamers play together.

Crowdstar

2 years 1 month

Sr. Mobile Marketing Manager January 2013 - November 2013 (11 months) Burlingame, CA

Led the marketing team at Crowdstar and worked directly with executive management to manage overall marketing strategy.

Designed and managed launch strategy of new mobile games for one of the top mobile gaming companies in the world. Created user acquisition plans for multi-million dollar marketing budgets. Managed strategy, forecasting, media buying, creative direction, analytics, and execution for highly successful titles like Covet Fashion, Mermaid World, Fish with Attitude, Modern Girl, and Top Girl franchises.

Online & Mobile Marketing Manager November 2011 - January 2013 (1 year 3 months) Burlingame, CA Epsilon
Marketing Account Manager
March 2009 - November 2011 (2 years 9 months)
#1 US Direct Marketing Agency - Ad Age, 2009

Injecting science into the art of marketing...

I worked with Epsilon's clients to improve the effectiveness of their relationship marketing. I helped companies better understand the impact relationship marketing/CRM has on their business and how to improve it's success through analytics and strategy. I consulted with leading biotech and healthcare clients on their CRM and marketing intelligence strategy.

Fisher Investments
1 year 4 months

Program Manager, Online Marketing July 2008 - November 2008 (5 months)

Managed strategic planning of \$14 million in online advertising resources for a financial services firm with over \$50 billion in assets. Directed all aspects of relationships with key online vendors, including media planning, media buying, and optimization using ROI analysis and campaign reporting metrics.

This experience really solidified my knowledge of how to run a highly successful online marketing program. Working daily with experts from some of the largest advertising & publishing firms in the world exposed me to a diverse field of the latest technology in customer targeting and ad deployment.

Program Manager, Marketing Materials Production August 2007 - September 2008 (1 year 2 months)

Led a cross-functional team of 10 people responsible for the design, production, and distribution of all marketing material. Directed the most efficient use of multi-million dollar annual budget to support marketing campaigns and optimize materials.

Drove numerous cost savings through contract negotiation and process improvements. Trained multiple new hires and managers. Collaborated on Direct Mail creative strategies and recommended test ideas that were consistent with business objectives.

SofTEQ

Marketing Consultant 2006 - 2007 (1 year)

Worked directly with CEO and COO to design and manage branding campaigns for SofTEQ Group. Assisted in redesign of corporate website, including creation and copyediting of 80+ pgs of content (www.softeggroup.com).

Improved brand image and visibility of company to potential clients.

Assisted in launch of industry resource center, including a "lunch-and-learn" educational seminar series.

Education

University of Colorado Boulder - Leeds School of Business Business Administration, Operations Management, Entrepreneurship and Small Business Management

Stanford Business School
N/A - Continuing Studies, Social Media Marketing

Lowell High School